Debugging HTML, debugging HTML
调试 HTML
I think is just one of the best ways that you could possibly learn how to code.
应该是你学习如何编程最好的方式之一
As a developer, you spent a great deal of time debugging your code,
作为一个开发者 你会花费很多时间来调试你的代码
trying to figure out where the errors are and how your code could be improved.
查找出现的错误原因以及如何优化你的代码
Debugging can often feel like a nuisance,
调试可能会让你感觉很麻烦
but it's really one of the foundations of
但它确实是编程的基础之一
programming and offers a great opportunity for learning.
而且可以让你学到很多
Debugging HTML is unique because there are no commands for feedback the way JavaScript,
调试 HTML 有一些特殊 因为没有可以查看反馈的命令
for example, has some built in error messaging and you
不像 JavaScript 会有一些内置的错误信息
can console.log functions out to help debug.
然后你可以使用 console.log 函数打印出来帮助调试
Debugging HTML often means just reading through
调试 HTML 通常需要你仔细阅读你的代码
your code line by line and looking for possible errors spots.
一行一行地查找可能出现错误的地方
So before I go too far in,
在我们进一步之前
let's make sure we understand what debugging is.
我们先弄清楚调试到底是什么意思
Debugging is a term that implies that when programs aren't working the way we want,
调试通常意味着我们的程序没有按照预期的方式运行
it's because there's bugs or errors,
因为某些错误
there's issues in them.
出现了一些问题
So debugging is the process of looking through your code to try to find the places where
所以 调试就是浏览你的代码 试着找到出现错误的地方
these bugs or errors are and then to resolve them in some way, and that's debugging.
然后以某种方式解决它们 这就是调试的过程
So what are some common HTML bugs?
那么 哪些是常见的 HTML 错误呢？
Mismatch opening and closing tags are probably the ones I've seen most often.
我所遇见最常见的错误是开始标签和结束标签不匹配
Now these are particularly dangerous because
这种情况是很危险的
the browser will still render them without any issue.
因为浏览器仍然可以渲染它们 并且没有任何提示
So you just won't see what you expect and you won't know what's going on.
所以你会看到和你预期不一样的情况 但是你不知道发生了什么
So here, if you look closely,
在这里 你可以看到
you can see that I have an h1 opener tag but an h2 closing tag,
我有一个开始的 h1 标签 但是却有一个结束的 h2 标签
very easy mistake to make when I do all the time,
这是很容易出现的错误
and very important to come through and closely look to make sure it's this an h1 or h2.
也非常重要 你需要仔细检查它们来确保它是 h1 或者 h2
I actually want it to be an h1.
我希望它是 h1
Now, this is an example,
这也是一个例子
a missing closing tag,
一个缺失的关闭标签
which you see it's such a terrible error that if I uncomment it,
如果我取消注释 这会是一个很糟糕的错误
it messes up the rest of my code because it's waiting here for that.
它会混淆我接下来的代码 因为它们就紧跟在后面
But without a closing block,
如果没有结束标签
it's going to keep reading.
它会继续解析
So essentially it thinks I'm trying to say,
最后的结果可能是
my h2 is all of this,
h2 既包含了这一部分
and then all of this and all the way through.
也包含了接下来的所有部分
So looking for closing tags can be a very,
所以 寻找结束标签可能是调试中非常非常
very, very important part of debugging.
重要的一部分
I would say the third most common thing I see is quotation errors,
第三种很常见的情况则是引号错误
because we use strings when we're writing.
因为我们在编写时会使用字符串
Strings are texts that are wrapped in between quotation marks.
字符串文本被放置在一堆引号之间
So to not have a closing one means that your string is going to go on forever.
如果没有结束引号 就意味着你的字符串会一直延续下去
There's what we want. Now we have the string here wrapped around in
这才是我们想要的结果 现在字符串被包裹在一对引号中
quotations and our string here wrapped around in quotations, and we're good to go.
一切都恢复了正常
Now, the question, is do you think you're
好了 现在的问题是
going to be able to debug an HTML file on your own?
你认为你自己能够调试 HTML 中的代码吗？
I'm confidence you can.
我相信你可以